Xavier University Faculty Committee records
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Xavier University Faculty Committee records
1952-2012
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Faculty Committee
1.6 linear feet (4 boxes)
Meeting minutes, related documents and correspondence of the Xavier University Faculty Committee.
XUA-17
History of Xavier University Faculty Committee
On March 9, 1952 a meeting of lay faculty members of Xavier University was held for the purpose of determining the feasibility of establishing a "faculty organization." After some months of consideration of this idea, the Faculty Committee was established with its first formal meeting occurring on October 9, 1953. The committee appears to have met regularly thereafter, some years more frequently than others.
The role of the Faculty Committee has changed with time. The Annual Document of University Committees provides the following information on the role, responsibilities, and membership of this committee: "THE FACULTY COMMITTEE: Charge: The Faculty Committee, elected annually by the faculty, is the official representative body of the faculty. This committee is advisory to the Academic Vice President/Provost and has access to the President. Membership: The Faculty Committee consists of nine (9) tenured or tenure-track faculty members elected by the faculty so as to provide two and no more than four members from any college. Their terms of office are three years. The Committee elects its own Chair. Reporting: The Faculty Committee reports to the Academic Vice President/Provost." (Source: Annual Document of University Committees, 2009-2010)
Scope and Content
Meeting minutes, related documents and correspondence stemming from the activities of the Xavier University Faculty Committee.
Not specified
Statement of Arrangement
Materials are arranged in this general manner:
Meeting minutes with related documents
Correspondence of Faculty Committee chairs
Separated Material
Faculty Committee minutes and other materials are also held digitally in the Xavier University Archives permanent storage drive. Years of inclusion are 2000 to the present.
Restrictions on Access
Restricted access. Please contact the Xavier University Archives staff.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio)--Faculty
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Faculty Committee Minutes and Attachments, 1952-1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Faculty Committee Minutes and Attachments, 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Faculty Committee Minutes and Attachments, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Faculty Committee Minutes and Attachments, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Faculty Committee Minutes and Attachments, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Faculty Committee Minutes and Attachments, 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Faculty Committee Minutes and Attachments, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Faculty Committee Minutes and Attachments, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Faculty Committee Minutes and Attachments, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Faculty Committee Minutes and Attachments, 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Faculty Committee Minutes and Attachments, 1980-1983 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Faculty Committee Minutes and Attachments, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Faculty Committee Minutes and Attachments, 1984-1988 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Faculty Committee Minutes and Attachments, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Faculty Committee Minutes and Attachments, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Faculty Committee Minutes and Attachments, 1990-1994 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Faculty Committee Minutes and Attachments, 1994-1997 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Faculty Committee Minutes and Attachments, 1997-1999 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Faculty Committee Minutes and Attachments, 1999-2002 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Faculty Committee Minutes and Attachments, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Faculty Committee Minutes and Attachments, 2003-2010 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Faculty Committee Cross Listing of Electronic Records Found in Archives Permanent Storage Drive, 2001-2012 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Faculty Committee Correspondence of Chair, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Faculty Committee Correspondence of Chair, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Faculty Committee Correspondence of Chair, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Faculty Committee Correspondence of Chair, 1996-1997 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Faculty Committee Correspondence of Chair, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Faculty Committee Correspondence of Chair, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Faculty Committee Correspondence of Chair, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Faculty Committee Correspondence of Chair, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 8)